Ambrose Ndone

Full Stack Web Developer

Nairobi

ambrosetall@gmail.com

+254 722 808670

I am a highly self motivated full Stack developer with experience in developing high quality software and writing high efficient and clean code according to specifications. With my experience and background education, I have gained a specialist understanding of translating complex problems into solutions by developing high quality software. I love learning new technologies to add and update on my existing skillset.

Work Experience

Full Stack Developer

DoWell Research - Singapore March 2022 to Present

At DoWell, I work in a team where we are working on different scale functions to be used in different products.

In my team, I work mostly as a Python developer where I write the scale functions and develop REST APIs using Django (framework). At times I can be tasked to work on the front end screens where I integrate the API endpoints to my front end application which I develop using React.

So far I have completed the back end of two scale functions with one fully completed (back end+ front end).

Software Developer

Innovex Solutions - Nairobi September 2022 to January 2023

I currently manage and add new features in two products (systems) designated to our team where both systems are procured by insurances whereby one digitizes the claim process when issuing vehicle accidental covers and the other system deals with part suppliers whom the insurance interact with to get the latest prices of any parts of any type of vehicle model. I work on both on front end and back end of the system with my team mates when adding or upgrading the features of the system as it is used by over 200 users including the entities under insurance companies. Technologies used are React, Node, Express, Next js, Angular js, SQL (MariaDB).

Software Developer Intern

Real Biz Digital - Nairobi January 2022 to March 2022

As an intern the organization provided materials to learn and advance my skills as a Software Developer. Learning programming languages.

Analysing different websites and identifying any pain points and suggest any ideas that can be made on the website.

IT Intern

Parliamentary Service Commission - Nairobi August 2021 to December 2021

Provided basic IT support and networking services.

Troubleshooting network related issues.

Troubleshooting printer related issues.

Connecting desktops and printers over network.

Managing the Parliamentary congress system.

I developed a e-board application which was used by the local staffs to schedule meeting and view agendas of the meeting as the organization's aim was to go paperless. I developed the e-board system using Python (Django), Html & Css and JavaScript.

Education

Bachelor's in Computer science

Laikipia University - Laikipia

September 2017 to August 2021

Skills

- Python (2 years)
- Django (2 years)
- JavaScript (2 years)
- React (2 years)
- Node.js (1 year)
- HTML5 (3 years)
- CSS (3 years)
- PostgreSQL (2 years)
- Docker (Less than 1 year)
- MongoDB (2 years)
- Relational databases (2 years)
- Git (1 year)
- APIs (2 years)
- JSON (2 years)
- REST (2 years)
- AWS (Less than 1 year)
- GitLab (Less than 1 year)
- MySQL (2 years)
- GraphQL (Less than 1 year)
- Microservices (1 year)
- Unit testing (1 year)
- GitHub

- Bootstrap
- Linux

Languages

- English Expert
- Swahili Expert

Links

https://github.com/AmbroTall

https://ndoneambrose.netlify.app/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ambrose-mbithi-963849214/

Certifications and Licenses

Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA)

January 2019 to Present

I was certified in CCNA 1, CCNA 2, CCNA 3 and CCNA 4

Linux

Present

Cisco Linux certification

JavaScript

January 2022 to Present

IBM Badge

React and ECMAScript

Present

IBM Badge

Web Development

February 2022 to Present

IBM Badge

Git

February 2022 to Present

IBM Badge